A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Activities, Series A FA338
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, Oral Histories (FA344)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, Politics - New York City Office (FA345)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, Politics - George L. Hinman (FA346)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, Politics - Oscar M. Ruebhausen (FA347)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, Projects (FA348)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, Speeches, Post-Vice Presidential (FA349)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, Washington, DC (FA350)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, Ann C. Whitman - Politics (FA351)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, Hugh Morrow Interviews (FA352)
International relations; International relations -- United States; United States; Latin America; Civic improvement; Business enterprises, Foreign; Agriculture; Government agencies; Federal government -- United States; New York (State); Education
- African Matters, 1956-1960, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  NAR considers investments in Africa after a trip there, no action taken. NAR sends $500 to Lester Granger's African Project. Correspondents include NAR, Lloyd V. Shaere, Stacy May.
- American-Colombian Corporation
  - General, 1941-1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    NAR and Laurance Spelman Rockefeller invest in corporation owning surface rights to large area in Colombia, 1941. Plans for development. Oil exploration. Surveys of land. Attempts to interest other investors and developers. Final decision to liquidate at a loss. Correspondents include NAR, Laurance Spelman Rockefeller, Ogden White, Randolph Marsten.
  - General, 1941-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agriculture, 1941-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Investigations of agricultural possibilities in Lands of Loba. Efforts to interest other investors. Final report negative. Correspondents include Ogden White.
  - Cattle, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Study of cattle raising possibilities in the Lands of Loba. Correspondents include Ogden White.
  - Curran and Cannon Reports (U.S. Forest Service), 1916, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Earlier studies of Land of Loba.
  - Knight, Jesse H., 1941-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Title clarification, oil leases. Correspondents include Laurance Spelman Rockefeller.
  - Lands of Loba, 1952-1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Rockefeller brothers investment in company owning development rights in a large tract of land in Colombia. Feasibilities studies, oil possibilities, negative reports. Laurance Spelman Rockefeller sells his stock. NAR sells his stock to International Basic Economy Corporation. Correspondents include NAR, Lawrence Long.
  - Legal Documents and Attachments, 1941-1950, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    William F. Coles report on Colombia land laws. Attempts to clarify titles to land. Correspondents include Ogden White.
  - Lewis, J. Whitney, 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Proposed effort to exploit timber resources on lands. Correspondents include Randolph B. Marston.
  - Maps (Colombia), 1928, 1934, 1937, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Maps of Lands of Loba and Colombia.
  - Minerals, 1927, 1940-1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Investigation of iron ore, petroleum and uranium possibilities. Correspondents include Ogden White.
  - Oil, 1941-1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Socony lease for exploration and development. (American-Colombia Corp.'s only source of income.)
  - Stock Holdings and Transactions, 1941-1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Stock valuations.
  - Stock Purchase Agreement, 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Purchase agreements with other stockholders.
  - Timber, 1909, 1916, 1945-1950 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Efforts to develop lumbering industry on Lands of Loba without success. 1916 study by H. M. Curran. Correspondents include Ogden White.
- American-European Associates, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  European venture capital investment, Rockefeller brothers held majority interest. No follow up here. Correspondents include NAR, John Davison Rockefeller 3rd.
- Amun-Israeli Housing Corporation
  - By-laws and Attachments, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Original and amended by-laws.
  - Financing and Bond Issue, 1950-1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Correspondence re: bond, use of NAR's signature on bonds. Correspondents include NAR, Francis A. Jamieson, Vera Goeller.
  - Financing and Bond Issue, 1950-1964 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Financing and Bond Issue, 1950-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - General Correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Organized to finance and build 8000 homes in Israel. NAR served on board and as vice president, made public appearances to raise funds. Large trade union participation. International Basic Economy Corporation bid on construction. Correspondents include NAR, George Dudley.
  - General Correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Appointment Books, 1932-1968
  NAR's daily professional activities.
  - 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1936-1941 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 1936-1941 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - 1936-1941 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - 1936-1941 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 1945-1948 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - 1945-1948 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - 1945-1948 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - 1945-1948 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 59)
- Appointments as Special Assistant to President Eisenhower (SAP), 1954-1956 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  Clippings and comments.
- Articles by and about NAR
  - Articles by NAR as Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA), 1940-1945, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 61)
    Drafts and copies of printed articles about inter-American affairs.
  - General, 1946-1971 (Box 12, Folder 62)
    Correspondence re: preparation and editing of articles by and about NAR.
  - General, 1946-1971 (Box 12, Folder 63)
  - "Advance", 1964 (Box 12, Folder 64)
    No copy of article here.
  - "Americas", 1949 (Box 12, Folder 65)
    Article by NAR re: Point IV.
  - "Art in America", 1957-1970 (Box 12, Folder 66)
    Article about NAR, 1958 (not in file), article by NAR, 1963 (copy in file), about NAR's sculpture collection by Francine du Plessis, 1965 (copy in file).
  - "The Art of Collecting", 1964 (Box 13, Folder 67)
    Transcript of television show, NAR interviewed by Aline Saarine.
  - "1955 Britannica Book of the Year", 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 68)
    Forward by NAR; "Western Hemisphere Interdependence and Unity". Comments.
  - "Cosmopolitan", 1963 (Box 13, Folder 69)
    Copies of article on Margaretta Fitler Rockefeller.
  - "Foreign Affairs", 1951-1968 (Box 13, Folder 70)
    Three articles by NAR, 1951, 1960, 1968.
  - "Fortune", 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 71)
    Correspondence re: article on the Rockefeller brothers, no copy of article here.
  - "Life", 1942-1965 (Box 13, Folder 72)
    Articles about NAR.
  - "Links", 1940 (Box 13, Folder 73)
    NAR article by NAR re: threat of war.
  - "New York Age", 1940 (Box 13, Folder 74)
    Request for interview, no copy of article here.
  - "New York Herald Tribune", 1958 (Box 13, Folder 75)
    Guest column by NAR, no copy here.
  - "New York Post", 1953, 1957-1958 (Box 13, Folder 76)
    Correspondence re: interviews for articles, copies of articles, columns.
  - "Newsweek", 1958 (Box 13, Folder 77)
    Correspondence re: interview for article on Rockefeller brothers, copy of article.
  - "Saturday Evening Post", 1938, 1943, 1940-1951, 1959, 1962, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 78)
    Article by John Cushman Fistere on Rockefeller brothers, 1938; article by NAR re: Latin America, 1943; series by Joe Alex Morris on Rockefeller brothers, 1950; "The Rockefeller Nobody Knows," by Stewart Alsop, 1959; article by NAR on art, 1971.
  - "Time", 1958 (Box 13, Folder 79)
    Copy of article about NAR.
  - "U.S. News and World Report", 1962 (Box 13, Folder 80)
    Copy of article by NAR, "A Plan for Growth and Jobs."
  - "Western World", 1957 (Box 13, Folder 81)
    Copy of article by NAR, "Latin America and the Western World."
- Astronauts, 1968, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 82)
  NAR's letters of congratulations to Apollo crews, their responses.
- Atom Bomb, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 83)
  NAR interest in defense against nuclear attack.
- Biographical Data on NAR, 1947-1971 (Box 14, Folder 85)
  Biographical sketches, time-lines, lists of club and association memberships. Requests for information on NAR.
- Biographical Data on NAR, 1947-1971 (Box 14, Folder 86)
- Biographies of NAR
  - Gervasi, Frank, "The Real Rockefeller," Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 87)
    Gervasi was a speech writer for NAR. Comments, criticisms, and corrections re: this endorsed biography produced for the 1964 presidential campaign. Correspondents include Frank Gervasi, Martha Dalrymple.
  - Irwin, Don, "Nelson A. Rockefeller in Government" - Copy #1 - Chapters I-V, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 88)
    Irwin was a speech writer for NAR. This unpublished, sympathetic narrative of NAR's service in local, state and federal government, 1933-1962, appears to have been produced for use as a reference for NAR's biographers and speech writers. Two photocopies of the original typescript.
  - Irwin, Don, "Nelson A. Rockefeller in Government" - Copy #1 - Chapters VI-VIII, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 89)
  - Irwin, Don, "Nelson A. Rockefeller in Government" - Copy #2 - Chapters I-V, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 90)
  - Irwin, Don, "Nelson A. Rockefeller in Government" - Copy #2 - Chapters VI-VIII, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 91)
  - Irwin, Don, "Nelson A. Rockefeller in Government" - Correspondence, 1960, 1963, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 92)
    Correspondents include Don Irwin, Roswell B. Perkins.
  - Morris, Joe Alex, "Nelson Rockefeller, A Biography" - Copy #1 - Chapters I-VII, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 93)
    Photocopies of two edited drafts.
  - Morris, Joe Alex, "Nelson Rockefeller, A Biography" - Copy #1 - Chapters VIII-XVII, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 94)
  - Morris, Joe Alex, "Nelson Rockefeller, A Biography" - Copy #2 - Chapters I-VII, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 95)
  - Morris, Joe Alex, "Nelson Rockefeller, A Biography" - Copy #2 - Chapters VIII-XVII, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 96)
  - Morris, Joe Alex, "Nelson Rockefeller, A Biography" - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 97)
    An endorsed biography produced for the 1960 presidential election. Correspondence re: Morris' use of NAR's files, quoting from John Davison Rockefeller, Jr.'s letters, photographs, publication.
- Books and lectures by NAR
  - "The Future of Federalism" - Arabic Translation, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 98)
    Based on NAR's three lectures at the Godkin Lectures series, Harvard University, February 7 - 9, 1962.
  - "The Future of Federalism" - Clippings and Reviews, 1962-1963 (Box 16, Folder 99)
  - "The Future of Federalism" - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 100)
    Based on NAR's three lectures at the Godkin Lectures series, Harvard University, February 7 - 9, 1962. Preparation of text, comments, publication and distribution. Correspondents include NAR, Henry Kissinger, Hugh Morrow, Emmet J. Hughes.
  - "Godkin Lectures," Harvard University - Speaker's Copy, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 101)
    NAR's annotated copy of lectures.
  - "Godkin Lectures," Harvard University - Speaker's Copy, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 102)
  - "Godkin Lectures," Harvard University - Correspondence, 1960-1962, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 103)
  - "Godkin Lectures," Harvard University - Publicity, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 104)
  - "Godkin Lectures," Harvard University - Transcript of Question/Answer Session, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 105)
  - "Our Environment Can Be Saved", 1970 (Box 17, Folder 106)
    Correspondence re: publication and distribution.
  - "The U.S. and the World"
    Unpublished manuscript of NAR's thoughts on U.S. foreign policy and the future role of the United States as a global power. James Monahan and Lois Mattox Monahan, husband and wife, were hired as ghost writers. NAR abandoned the project when President Harry Truman appointed him chair of the International Development Advisory Board in November 1950. NAR included his thoughts on the subject in the IDAB's final report, "Partners in Progress."
    - Correspondence, 1949-1956 (Box 17, Folder 107)
      Agreement with Monahans; gathering information on Latin America, American International Association for Social and Economic Development, and International Basic Economy Corporation. Offers to publish the book or portions of it. Correspondents include, NAR, James Monahan, Lois M. Monahan, Francis A. Jamieson.
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 108)
      NAR's undated, handwritten notes and outlines, on poster paper.
    - Notes and Memoranda, 1949-1950 (Box 17, Folder 109)
      NAR's undated, handwritten notes and outlines on yellow pads and note cards; letter from Victor Borella with anecdotes from the "inter-American period."
    - Notes and Memoranda, 1949-1950 (Box 17, Folder 110)
    - Outlines and Drafts, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 111)
      Outlines and drafts handwritten by NAR.
    - Transcript Outlines, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 112)
    - Transcripts of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, February 7 - March 14, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 113)
    - Transcripts of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, March 21 - April 7, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 114)
    - Transcripts of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, May-June 1949 (Box 18, Folder 115)
    - Edited Transcripts of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 116)
      Arranged by subject matter: Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs; International Basic Economy Corporation; American International Association for Social and Economic Development. pp. i-iv, 5-38.
    - Edited Transcripts of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 117)
      Arranged by subject matter: Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs; International Basic Economy Corporation; American International Association for Social and Economic Development. pp. 39-79.
    - Edited Transcripts of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 118)
      Arranged by subject matter: Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs; International Basic Economy Corporation; American International Association for Social and Economic Development. pp. 80-108.
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 119)
      pp. 1-53
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 120)
      pp. 1-149
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 121)
      pp. 150-262
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 122)
      pp. 263-359
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 123)
      pp. 360-469
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 124)
      pp. 531-[838]
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 125)
      pp. 1-262: U.S. citizens and the world; formation, composition and nature of "the group;" NAR's trips to Latin America; Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA). Revised 1/1-2/10/50.
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 126)
      pp. 263-359: Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) programs, policies and projects. Revised 2/7-2/13/50.
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 127)
      pp. 360-469: Argentina and hemispheric unity. Revised 3/21-3/31/50.
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 128)
      pp. 470-621: Argentina, Mexico City Conference. Revised 3/31-4/11/50.
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 129)
      pp. 622-753: United Nations San Francisco Conference. Revised 4/11-5/16/50.
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan - Copy 2, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 130)
      pp. 1-197
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan - Copy 2, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 131)
      pp. 198-359
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan - Copy 2, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 132)
      pp. 360-621
    - Revised Transcript of NAR's Conversations with Mr. and Mrs. Monahan - Copy 3, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 133)
      pp. 214-311c
    - Monahan Draft - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 134)
      NAR's account of his Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) activities and the beginning of American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA) and International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), revised by James Monahan on May 12, 1950. Chapters I-VI.
    - Monahan Draft - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 135)
      NAR's account of his Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) activities and the beginning of American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA) and International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), revised by James Monahan on May 12, 1950. Chapters VII-XII.
    - Monahan Draft - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 136)
      NAR's account of his Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) activities and the beginning of American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA) and International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), revised by James Monahan on May 12, 1950. Chapters XIII-XXVII.
    - Monahan Draft - Copy 2, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 137)
      NAR's account of his Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) activities and the beginning of American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA) and International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), revised by James Monahan on May 12, 1950. Chapters I-XII.
    - Monahan Draft - Copy 2, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 138)
      NAR's account of his Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) activities and the beginning of American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA) and International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), revised by James Monahan on May 12, 1950. Chapters XIII-XV.
    - Adolf A. Berle Revisions - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 139)
      Parts I-III
    - Adolf A. Berle Revisions - Copy 1, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 140)
      Parts IV-V
    - Adolf A. Berle Revisions - Copy 2, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 141)
    - Reference Files, Card Index to (Box 23, Folder 142)
    - Reference File No. 1, ca. 1940-1950 (Box 23, Folder 143)
      Formation of United Nations; foreign investment; timelines of NAR's activities and trips, 1934-1947; meetings with President Franklin Roosevelt.
    - Reference File No. 2, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 144)
      Newspaper clippings re: foreign trade; labor; oil; Point IV; foreign investment; Russia; China; Germany; United Nations.
    - Reference File No. 3, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 145)
      Works by Henry Cantril: "The Why of Man's Experience," 1950; excerpts from "The Behavior of Men," with comments by NAR; "Further Notes Toward an Understanding of Human Behavior: Values, Choice and Action," with marginal notes by NAR.
    - Reference File No. 4, 1949 (Box 023A, Folder 146)
      "National Security and Our Individual Freedom," by the Committee for Economic Development.
    - Reference File No. 5 - Part 1, 1949-1950 (Box 023A, Folder 147)
      NAR's outlines and drafts on post-war private economic action.
    - Reference File No. 5 - Part 2, 1949-1950 (Box 023A, Folder 148)
    - Reference File No. 6, 1949 (Box 023A, Folder 149)
      Printed material on world trade and foreign investment. "Can Western Europe Help Itself?" by Imrie de Vegh, 1949, contains NAR's marginal notes.
    - Reference File No. 7, 1948-1950 (Box 023A, Folder 150)
      Printed material on foreign investment; addresses by NAR, A. H. Vandenberg, and Adolf A. Berle.
    - Reference File No. 8, 1949-1950 (Box 023A, Folder 151)
      Outlines for book by NAR, James Monahan, and Adolf A. Berle.
    - Reference File No. 9 - Part 1, 1950 (Box 023A, Folder 152)
      James Monahan's drafts of chapters I-II.
    - Reference File No. 9 - Part 2, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 153)
      James Monahan's early draft of chapters I-XIV, with NAR's marginal notes.
    - Reference File No. 10, 1948-1950 (Box 24, Folder 154)
    - Documents and Research Files, 1940-1950
      Memos, notes, revisions of drafts, and NAR's comments divided into the following sub-files within this folder: Miscellaneous (includes list of members of "the group"); Argentina; Development Corporations; Editorials, Use of; European Aid; Oil - Mexico; Rio de Janeiro Conference; "Dumbarton Oaks and the Small Nations," from John Foster Dulles' "War or Peace;" Mexico City Conference; San Francisco Conference.
      - Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs Correspondence, 1940-1946 (Box 24, Folder 155)
        Correspondence cited in Rowland's history of the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (OCIAA).
      - Rowland, Donald, "History of the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs", 1947 (Box 24, Folder 156)
      - Drafts and Outlines, Section III, 1949-1950 (Box 24, Folder 157)
      - "Point Four" and Foreign Trade Material, 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 158)
      - "Point Four" and Foreign Trade Material, 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 159)
      - "Point Four" and Foreign Trade Material, 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 160)
      - "Point Four" and Foreign Trade Material, 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 161)
      - Miscellaneous Files on AIA, 1941, 1946-1947, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 162)
      - Miscellaneous Files on AIA, 1941, 1946-1947, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 163)
      - Miscellaneous Files on Foreign Trade, 1945, 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 164)
      - Miscellaneous Files on Aid to Latin America, 1945-1946, 1948-1950 (Box 26, Folder 165)
      - Miscellaneous Files on Aid to Latin America, 1945-1946, 1948-1950 (Box 26, Folder 166)
      - Miscellaneous Files on Aid to Latin America, 1945-1946, 1948-1950 (Box 26, Folder 167)
- Books by Others - Guerrant, E. O., "Roosevelt's Good-Neighbor Policy" - Galley Proof, 1949-1950 (Box 26, Folder 168)
  Sent to NAR for comment. NAR explains his position in Argentinean recognition issue. His long letter was reduced to three sentences in this book. Correspondents include NAR, Francis A. Jamieson.
- Capitol Hill Associates/Capitol Hill Club
  - General, 1949-1971 (Box 26, Folder 169)
    Correspondence re; Capitol Hill Realty Corp.; renovation of Washington Inn in Washington DC for use as a Republican Center; purchase of stock, membership, notices of meetings; NAR contributions for gifts, portraits, James C. Auchincloss Room; cancellation of NAR loans. List of founders. Correspondents include NAR, James C. Auchincloss.
  - General, 1949-1971 (Box 26, Folder 170)
  - Certificates of Incorporation and By-laws, 1950-1951 (Box 27, Folder 171)
  - Printed Material, 1950-1953 (Box 27, Folder 172)
  - Subscriptions to Common Stock, 1951-1960 (Box 27, Folder 173)